# Mark Carpenter Jr

Aspiring Mobile-First Web Developer

marksthings24@gmail.com

## Summary

We live in a connected world and I'm not afraid of that, matter of fact there isn't much I fear, be it new things, further educating myself or even change. Developing cutting edge mobile applications is a passion of mine, by nature I am a creator, sculpting what ever medium I can find, into sometimes abstract, but most of the time realist functional objects. As of right now I'm all about Polymer by Google, their new approach to Material Design and Frameworks, in my opinion, is going to really set a high standard for user interaction with mobile applications and how they are built. One of my biggest pet peeves about the internet today; it's not very mobile friendly, with mobile devices playing such a large role in how people Receive, Collect, Modify and Distribute data, stressing the Receive. It blows my mind that larger media outlets and institutions have web presence that is not mobile friendly. Obscured display, tiny touch targets, and inaccessible features are just a few key examples. Ultimately I see myself in the future as part of a team of developers and designers working to create the web applications of tomorrow on bleeding edge web technologies. While my manufacturing experience may not seem relevant in the web technology field, my knowledge and logical thinking will help to create breakout and cutting edge web and mobile applications.

# Experience

CNC Machinist at G. P. Tool Co.

August 2014 - Present (1 year)

Operations Manager at M. T. J. Manufacturing, INC.

January 2003 - July 2014 (11 years 7 months)

#### **CNC Machinist at NAIAD Dynamics**

June 2009 - April 2013 (3 years 11 months)

## Skills & Expertise

Strategic Planning
New Business Development
Marketing Strategy
Project Management
Management
Leadership
Public Speaking
Microsoft Office

**Sales** 

**Social Media Marketing** 

**Team Building** 

**Team Leadership** 

**Web Development** 

**Web Applications** 

**Mobile Applications** 

**CSS** 

**Semantic HTML** 

**JavaScript** 

CodeIgniter

Joomla

WordPress

CAD/CAM

**Manufacturing Operations** 

**CNC Manufacturing** 

## Education

## **Udacity**

Nanodegree, Frontend Web Developement, 2015 - 2016

#### **Interests**

New Technology, Mechanics, Fresh Air and Sunshine, Skiing, Golfing, Music some Talk Radio and Video Games... really.

## Languages

## **English**

#### Courses

## Nanodegree, Frontend Web Developement

Udacity

Responsive Web Design Fundementals

HTML and CSS

Responsive Images

**Javascript Basics** 

Intro to Jquery

Object-Oriented JavaScript

# **Projects**

## @dotMobi Contact Form

February 2015 to Present

Members: Mark Carpenter Jr

The @dotMobi Contact form is a Bootstrapped AngularJS SPWA (Single Page Web Applicaction) designed to allow potential contacts reach out. The AJAX form is configured to collect Name, Phone, and Email plus a message from the potential contact. Using PHPMail it then sends the message and information to an email address of your choice. I am currently working on vCard support to automatically build and send contact information as a vCard as well as send contact information the Application administrator selects to the sender in vCard format.

#### Unicorn Run, a JavaScript Game.

July 2015 to Present

Members: Mark Carpenter Jr

This is a HTML5 Canvas game created from a Forked GitHub project provided by Udacity. I worked to complete the JS and restyle the CSS to give it my own personal touch.

#### **MeMe Generator**

July 2015 to Present

Members:Mark Carpenter Jr

Awesome MeMe Generator from a Udacity lesson that I am currently working on Optimising for all devices. It uses Polymer 1.0 for it's styling.

# **Mark Carpenter Jr**

Aspiring Mobile-First Web Developer

marksthings24@gmail.com



Contact Mark on LinkedIn